This next talk is all about when with Max.
You know, it's all about this, so I'll hand you straight over.
Over to you, Max.
Thank you. Hi. Good afternoon.
How are you? Good. Tired?
Kind of. Right.
Well, time to start.
So we are going to talk about how to make your web apps, our web apps,
faster and cheaper for coding agents, actually, for every kind of agent.
So really quickly.
My name is Maximiliano. I can go by Max. It's a long name.
I'm from Argentina, so I live in Buenos Aires
and I've been an app developer for almost 30 years.
Right?
A web developer for 30 years and also done mobile apps.
And I have some books, online courses at different providers,
and I'm also Codex and from OpenAI,
and I'm writing a new book on Vanilla Web, remember books, right.
Papers in paper when I'm writing one that is not just for humans,
but also for agents.
Because when you are depending less
on additional libraries and frameworks and dependencies,
not you're not just more secure, but also it's better for the context.
Anyway, we are here to talk about how agents
and the web are working together, and right now
both are working together in different ways.
Of course, this is just kind of a starting, right?
We are in early, early days in terms of the agent web.
That's kind of a name.
So we know that agents wants to build for the web.
So when most people, even by coders are asking
for an app, I mean, the result is just a web app, right?
So the web is kind of the, the in prime time
when you are doing with coding, but also the web.
The web wants to run agents.
This is also kind of a starting, but now you can inject in your web apps
or your website different agents in different ways.
You can inject an agent that can run within a web app.
And now we can be a social network or whatever
that can be running directly in JavaScript.
And also you have something known as MCP apps
that are actually running, for example, inside Claude or inside ChatGPT.
Inside AI apps and web apps are running inside like a mini app.
That's kind of a name frame.
And there you can also have a web app that is actually running inside
an agent.
Also, users wants to browse the web
using agents H browsers.
Now, now Chrome at least in the US and another countries you have Gemini.
There you have it at.
So while the user is actually browsing a website,
the user can actually access a chatbot or an agent to do something on that website.
And also agents by themselves want to want to browse the web.
So in different ways.
So today we will focus on those three items okay.
On a solution that we have or that we will have
that will let us help us web developers.
So we are web developers and we want to enhance
the ability of agents to work with that.
So we know that we have the work app coming in a few days.
So let's say we created a website or a web app
to actually follow the World Cup, the FIFA World Cup.
So you have a way to search for matches.
You can follow your team okay.
And you have things like date picker.
So you can see the match that you have on on each date.
So if you are asking any any agent it can be open claw.
It can be Codex, it can be closed code.
You actually check information on this website.
It may take time to understand the user interface.
There are many ways that agents are today accessing the web, but it takes time
and also context and money tokens.
So it takes time, tokens and context.
And we know that the context window is also a problem, not just token usage.
So for example, if you want to see a round of 16, the semifinals and the final.
So all the information that you have here for a nation to actually understand
the information will take time, maybe a couple of minutes
to actually browse that website as a user and get that information.
So when Asians are browsing the web today, they're using several techniques.
First, you can create a connector or you can use
or you can ask the agent to use a connector.
A connector can be just an MCP server that of course the website or the web
app or the company behind that website
has to implement or a CLI.
I know you you probably something on NPN.
So then you have an NTP command that you can execute
or the agent can execute in the terminal if it has permission
to actually get the data from your service,
then we have the old fashioned way
to fetch to make an HTTP request.
The problem is that when an agent is trying to use
that technique, such as curl, it won't execute.
Any JavaScript or any user interface is just getting the HTML from the server.
So if it's a single page
application, it's not working, so you're not getting a real data.
Of course, you can use now browser usage.
On many occasions, it's like a plugin that you can install
mostly on Google Chrome or Chromium based browsers.
From for example, you have one, you have another one for codecs.
In that case the agent, the coordination can talk to that plugin
and that plugin can read your Dom and other parts.
It can be also the accessibility tree and
it can take a screenshot from from JavaScript.
It's taking a screenshot from child script, and you can analyze the content.
So it can be the browser plugin or even an internal browser.
For example, Codex today has an internal browser,
so it has its own browser that is kind of a web web view
based browser that can also use the agent to browse the web as a user.
And finally, at the last step, you have computer usage.
For example, these days, if you want to for some reason,
you want your coding nation to use Safari because you want to see you.
You want to test how Safari is rendered in a website.
It's not so simple for Asians today
at least to actually connect to Safari.
So there's just using computer usage that is just using your computer,
like using the mouse, the cursor,
taking a screenshots of the whole app and is using the app.
So the problem is that Asians are burning
when the browser is just a guessing game here.
So it's observing a screenshots, the Dom or the accessibility tree.
Then it's inferring what needs to be done.
So I need to click there.
I need to click on the date picker.
Then I need to take another screenshot for example.
I need to activate over that inferred data such as I need to click on that calendar
icon to actually see that there is a calendar that is been open.
And of course we need to repair
or repeat this because yeah, when I click on the calendar,
I need to take a new screenshot and then see what's happening on the page.
So this is consuming a lot of again, tokens.
Okay.
Time and context from our window from our context window.
So it's a problem.
So we need a new solution.
That's kind of the idea.
And web MCB is here
to try to solve solve some of this problem.
Maybe not all the problems but some of the problems.
Because when will let the front end expose capabilities and not just pixels.
So without Wembley the agent is
watching is analyzing is inferring over
pixels selectors Dom guesses or retry.
And with retry loops again every time it clicks in each retry.
And it's using image models or multi-modal models that are consuming more tokens
and a lot of time to analyze what's on the screen and where to click.
And now we are passing from inference
to a contract that we as a web developer define.
That's where in this case we are going to expose tools.
The tool will have a name, a description, a JSON, a schema.
I will show you a sample in a second and an execution function.
Then the in this case it may be JavaScript, for example
a JavaScript function, then that the agent can actually execute.
So instead of inferring as a user with with the UI,
we have a contract, we are exposing an interface to the agent.
So but maybe you are thinking but we already have MCP.
Why do we need web MCP?
Well actually the agent is kind of
in the middle here is planning on it can use MCP,
but MCP is kind of connected only to the back end.
So MCP is kind of the way to connect an agent
directly to the backend servers, APIs, data, workflows.
And that has some challenges authentication challenges
on some websites, maybe the user has some local storage
in index, CV or in web storage or in any other.
It can also be the file, the user file system.
Because we have a file system API, the user can also
be talking about sensors.
Right now.
For example, we have web apps for the meta display glasses.
So you can run JavaScript and web apps in your glasses
and you have sensors there.
Well,
maybe the agent that can be running in your class needs data from the sensors.
You are not going to get that from the back end from the server, right?
So that's why we have WebMCP.
That is kind of the way that we have to talk to the front end.
Right.
So it's not one or the other.
It's actually both.
It depends on what do you need.
You will be using an MCP server or an older web
MCP tool that you are exposing in your web app.
The web MCP then has access to the front end,
and that means the current page where you are the scroll, where the scroll is.
If you have a form, the data that the user or the agent
has typed into that form, you have, that's the
UI state, the whole user
session, and every client API.
Maybe you have a serial, a web serial device
connected to that machine, and then you can use that.
Okay.
So this is important when inspired by MCP but not inherited from.
So it's not actually the same protocol.
It has similar ideas to expose tools to the agent,
but it's not really the same API.
So the other day I've seen it on Twitter I don't remember x.
Sorry x, I don't remember the user, but he said
that when he is to MCP
as JavaScript is to Java,
okay, which is not a bad definition actually.
Okay, so it's inspired by the same idea
exposing tools to the agent, but it's not using the same protocols.
It's completely different. Okay.
So web it's a proposed standard API.
So it's not yet
the recommendation from the W3C, but it's going into that direction.
The author, in this case the website author is
then providing tools for the context of AI Asians.
We're actually going to be a chatbot as well.
But is it more suitable for AI agents?
So what's a tool? So the name here is tool.
Well it's just can be any function.
It can be any form that you have in your website.
So I mean you are receiving support tickets.
So you have a form.
Well that can be a tool
receiving form data for a new ticket for a new support ticket.
It's actually a tool.
It's it's going to be in origin trial tomorrow.
So if you are watching this session live tomorrow
we will have Chrome 149 and it's going to be narration trial,
meaning that you can start using it with real users out there.
If not, you can enable a flag or run chrome with a flag.
And also you can try this, but if you're watching this
in a recording session, then it's probably already there.
And of course, Asians will fall back to any other technique
if the tools are not provided by the website.
So it's important here to understand that when he needs your work.
So you need to implement web MCB if you want it.
It's not going to appear automatically in your websites.
So for coding Asians in particular,
because it can be also open close, it can be any Asian.
But for coding nations in particular it doesn't replace testing.
This is important.
It's not going to replace testing.
Testing is to test the user behavior.
So as a user you test as a user maybe including
now you have another test to make.
So if you have web you can also do unit testing over your tools.
So you need more testing actually.
So but it will later use tools on web apps faster and cheaper.
Not chapter cheaper.
And it will let you feel forms.
It will let the agent field forms on the web with better results
without actually guessing what should we feel and where.
So that's kind of the idea.
And this is interesting.
You can create log and debug tools that
then you can use with your current testing solutions.
So you can actually gather data in the frontend
for your test suite that
then you can run and get from Wema.
So for example you can expose list of errors.
So you can expose a tool that will collect.
So in which you collect all the errors happening in that current session
and that with when you get a list of those errors.
Or you can run diagnostics again with the full browser context.
In the front end you can describe the current view.
You can get like the Dom from the current view.
See them verify to know the the state
and to actually see this in action.
Every tool is just an object.
The object will have a name, descriptive name, a description.
This is interesting.
The description should be written not for humans but for Asians.
So we need to understand that our customer is an AI agent, not the user.
Right.
And then we have an input schema
where we're going to specify that's the input schema.
We're going to specify the information, the parameters, the arguments
that that particular tool will need from the agent.
And finally we have an execute function
that it's going to be executed by the web runner.
When the agent decides
to actually use that particular tool.
So the agent will, as with MCP,
the agent will collect, will ask the browser or will act your web
app, actually all the tools that you currently have available.
And based on that and based on the prompt or the goal from the agent,
it will execute. Then one of those tools
we have
on Chrome, a web inspector that looks like this.
For example, this is a fly search.
This is borrow from the Chrome team.
That example that is kind of the standard example when we're talking about
something about okay, let's do a fly search, let's do a hotel search.
And instead of
writing the things in the form you call a tool.
So from choice function.
But for our demo, the work app website is going to look like this.
For example, if I assume in into the Wemyss tools available
I can have get matches by date,
get team matches receiving the team list, groups,
leaves teams, search matches and so on.
That's the name.
Then we have a description and the input schema.
So for example, if I'm asking when is the second match for England, it's
going to give me an answer
based on executing the tool.
If I ask is it possible to see a final between
Argentina and England for example?
In this case it makes several calls to several tools with different arguments.
The Asian.
The Asian is making these calls and then it's giving me an answer.
And yes, we can have a final between England and Argentina.
And these are the two options.
So one needs to win the group and the other one needs to be runner
up in the group.
So if not they're going to
meet in the semifinals.
Even I can ask something like this.
Who will win the Cup?
Okay.
And I'm I'm not sure if I want to show you the next slide.
Remember, I'm from Argentina and I want to go home safe tomorrow, so.
But anyway, I can show you this is the answer from
the tool.
Okay.
Actually, we had that final. Okay.
Of course it can be.
This is Gemini by the way.
So the model behind this in Chrome is Gemini.
So Gemini is calling all the tools and see this is the answer anyway.
So the APIs actually are available in two forms.
You can use imperative API.
And that's our script okay.
You expose the tools as JavaScript functions.
And we had declarative API that in this case we use HTML forms.
So it's actually pretty simple.
So for example this is the imperative API
where you call document model context register tool.
And you pass the object that I mentioned before including the execute function.
That's all.
Of course, you can register several tools.
You don't need to register all the tools on the page load
based on the context of the app.
In one particular state of the app, you can have a set of tools
that may change over time, so you can remove tools.
You can register and register tools based on how
the state of the app is, is evolving or changing.
So execute expects a promise.
So actually any async operation will work.
So if your frontend needs to also execute, your back end is fine.
Or maybe you need to talk to a Bluetooth device and that's an async operation.
Well it's fine.
You can still use web tools for that.
And the other one, the declarative API, is just a form
where you define tool name and tool description.
Those are kind of the two mandatory option.
You also have a tool auto submit boolean attribute that you can define.
If you want to express that as a website author,
you you accept that form
to be auto submitted by the agent. Okay.
And then if you want if you want you on your form
elements, on input elements, text areas, select
or web components that are form elements, you can define the tool
parameter description that will add more information to the
on what needs to be filled there.
If you feel that the
maybe the label is not enough, but if you feel that the label is enough.
For example, for the first name you don't need to add it is optional.
So then the agent will see that and say okay, we have the create ticket
tool available and these are the arguments.
So the biggest question is does it random?
Well do you think that's the only way that we have these days
to see if a technology is powerful enough. Right.
So then I did this. So
there are some doom engines out there open source engines.
And I added a web CP to it.
So for example it's it's running doom.
You can hear that right. So.
There are a couple of tools there.
And I can actually say for example, hey,
so move forward for 10s.
And it's now running and now it's running doom.
It's not just running one one tool at a time.
You can also say rotate and move,
because the agent can run more than one tool at a time.
And also I can say something like and look at this.
You see that this is really powerful.
Play doom as a maniac for one minute okay?
So it takes time and it trusts playing
doom as a maniac using web MCP.
Okay, so who is playing doom?
The ancient okay is playing doom.
So using web MCP.
Okay, you got the idea, right?
So now Asians can play doom,
but then if you if you want to use this today okay.
In a coordination I mean in closed code in cursor in OpenAI Codex.
So how can I use it.
Well we have a bridge today that we can use.
That is an MCP tool to not web MCP
and MCP tool from Chrome Dev Tools.
So Chrome now is offering dev tools as an MCP tool.
And through that MCP tool you can actually run Wemyss.
So in this case you have a code nation when you go that supports MCP.
So all of them then you connect it to Deb tools MCP
Deb to NCP then creates a chrome engine chrome instance.
By the way web MCB doesn't work, at least now on headless browsers
because it's more suitable for a real, real context.
But this may change.
So we have a live chrome, and over that live chrome it's
going to run a website or a web app doom, for example.
And then it will list all the tools available
and it will execute the tools through that channel.
So if you want to play with this today, you can do that using this flow okay.
So if you want to play doom now on cloud code you know how to do that.
So in the future we may expect browser
tools from coordination to support web directly.
So then we don't need that bridge.
For example codecs may include directly web
support ChatGPT for MCP apps can support that.
Or when you have a browsing plugin for open claw,
it can support web directly.
Okay, but this is still experimental.
So to design tools is kind of designing an API.
So it's an API. So what's a tool.
What's when you are creating your web MCC list of tools you are designing an API.
But it's important that the consumer is the model not the user.
So some ideas use only one purpose per tool.
So don't create tools that are overlapping.
So then you are decreasing the
or you're
increasing the ability of the agent
to run the right tool for each situation.
So be a state aware and only when useful.
This is what I said before that you don't need to register all your tools at once,
because I know if it's a web app, maybe you are logged in,
or maybe you are logged out and tools may not be the same on those situations.
Okay, so plain language.
Describe what happens.
Remember this is going to be accessed by a model
by an agent that is using a model.
So you are speaking to a model basically.
So a strict code return meaningful errors.
Remember your consumer is not the user is the AI agent.
So you can actually respond with technical errors of okay the like
the parameters the arguments are wrong and what's going on.
So then the agent can iterate and solve those issues
without any human intervention and try to return and small output
exactly what has been requested.
By the way, for example, in the doom example.
So I created a couple of tools for of course
moving and also to get information about what you see on the screen.
You can get a screenshot in 64 as a Pag,
and also you can get information about your current position in the map.
And I'm trying to guess if you are to guess
if you are towards a wall or not, that's a boolean.
Okay, so those are the tools that I'm exposing.
Of course, there are more tools or less tools
that you can expose based on the engine what the ancient is, is providing you.
So this is really promising.
But also remember that this is still experimental.
There are a lot of discussions going on in terms of
what should be added or removed from the spec.
Okay, with all the actors around Asians, but right now, okay,
we have already passed the today today live with this session live.
It's a founder under discussion and it's under a Chrome flag.
So you need to enable the flag in Chrome.
But again tomorrow it's going to be in origin trial,
which means that you can fill a form and with your the origin of your website,
and you will be able to use it directly in Chrome as it as a trial.
So it means that the final API may change in a couple of months maybe.
And it's also available in puppeteer.
We are an experimental fly, so if you want to use it with puppeteer,
it's also available these days. For example.
That's something that you can use from a coding agent.
So it's the best
moment to learn from it to start discussing the
if you want to add support for it to enable like cheaper
and better access to your web app from any agent, including coronations.
So just one suggestion for you if you want to start
using this in your coding agent flow.
Okay, so you can pick just one high value page, state that you have in your web app
and expose every only diagnostic tool
from that state from your web app.
Then you evaluate that with calls and arguments.
And you of course, we are going to use that
from Claude Code, from Cursor, from OpenAI Codex, wherever you are using.
Then you automate that using DevTools, MCP or puppeteer.
Those are the two options that we have today.
Maybe in a couple of months it's going to be like native
for the rest of the AI agents, but not today.
That then it will look like this.
You will be able to ask, why is this page failing QA and you will
the tool will run.
The tool is going to be run diagnostics.
So we are going to with WebMCP.
We can make web app faster and cheaper for coding agents.
Remember it's an experimental API.
It will expose tools to the agent from the front end, not the back end.
That's the difference with MCP.
It will use the full browser context and you can use it right now with origin
trial in Chrome for end users or using Chrome dev
tools, MCP or puppeteer.
Okay, so having said that and with two seconds left.
Thank you.